Kevan Barter

kcbarter@msn.com (360) 402-9986 kcbarter.github.io/kevanbarterportfolio/ www.linkedin.com/in/KevanBarter https://github.com/kcbarter

Summary

Software Engineer experienced in developing full-stack web applications, specializing in Java, TypeScript, and ReactJS. Possessing a strong background in TDD, Agile methodologies, and testing frameworks. Ready to contribute to your team with my diverse skillset and excited to take on new challenges.

Skills

- Java, Typescript, JavaScript, Git, HTML, Tailwind CSS, SQL, MongoDB, CSS, SCSS, Python, C#, Node
- Springboot, ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, Thymeleaf, Gradle, Android Development, REST, HTTP protocol, Axios API
- TDD, Agile Methodologies, Unit Testing, CI/CD, Playwright, Selenium, JUnit, Jest

Professional Experience

Chenega Agile Real-Time Solutions | Software Engineer | Remote/Hybrid

Feb 2024 - Present

- Develop and maintain responsive web applications using ReactJS and Typescript.
- Implement efficient state management with Redux Toolkit for scalable data flow.
- Utilize Tailwind CSS for modern and visually appealing user interfaces.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to understand project requirements and provide technical insights.
- Contribute to the agile development processes through code reviews and continues integration/continuous development.
- Utilized GitHub version control to keep feature branches up to date and make daily commits.

Maximus | Software Engineer | Remote/Hybrid

Dec 2023 - Jan 2023

- Assisted in developing and maintaining responsive web applications using ReactJS, Typescript, and TailwindCSS.
- Contributed to fetching data with GraphQL requests for efficient data retrieval and management.
- Supported agile development processes through participation in code reviews, version control using GitHub, and collaboration with senior developers.

Microsoft | Software Engineer in Test | Remote/Hybrid

Sep 2022 - Dec 2023

- Migrated testing suite from Selenium to Playwright for Teams app.
- Strategically addressed legacy code challenges, seamlessly transitioning to new code without disrupting business operations.
- Collaborated with developers, PMs, and designers to identify and resolve issues in a timely manner.

Projects

Nitrouz Studioz | Software Engineer | GitHub

Jun 2019 – Present

- Developing a web application for users to create accounts and post in a forum type setting using Java, Spring Boot, SCSS, Thymeleaf, JavaScript, and SQL.
- Followed the MVC design pattern to better separate the project implementation and organized the SQL database so that the SQL tables were normalized.
- Created Model classes to represent SQL data and Controller classes that contained CRUD methods to manipulate/read from the database.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science, Northeastern University
Bachelor of Applied Science in Software Development, Green River College

Jan 2021 to Aug 2022 Sep 2016 to Jun 2019